KELSEY SIKES

STYLIST

CONTACT

- 731.661.1135
- sikes.kelsey@gmail.com
- St. Petersburg, FL
- www.linkedin.com/in/kelsey sikes/

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Arts: Fashion Design and Apparel Merchandising

Indiana University
Bloomington, IN | 2016

SKILLS

- Wardrobe styling
- Sales
- Relationship building
- Leadership
- Trend research
- Customer service chat
- MS Office Suite
- CRM programs
- Problem solving

PROFILE

Wardrobe Styling and sales professional with over five years experience in customer service and retail industries. Bringing to the table a reputation for creativity and effective solutions to business, sales, and customer issues. Adept leader, managing and developing high-performing teams of up to 20 serving customer base up to 800+. Drawing from breadth of retail industry expertise to style, cultivate, and grow supportive client relationships and deliver bottom line results.

EXPERIENCE

STYLE ADVISOR, LUXURY STORES STYLIST

AMAZON | VIRTUAL, DALLAS, TX | FEB 2021 - PRESENT

Curated wardrobe collections according to customers style and preferences resulting in sales metrics and customer satisfaction score above company average. Communicated with customers via chat platform providing a personalized experience and offering expert style advice.

- Advised clients on trends, curating personalized outfits to increase sales.
- Exceeded daily quota of collections styled, maintaining key KPI's.

ASSISTANT CUSTOMER SERVICE MANAGER

MODESENS | VIRTUAL, DALLAS, TX | NOV 2020 - FEB 2021

Managed all incoming and outgoing customer communications, prioritized heavy task load showing strong time management skills.

• Utilized online price comparison platform to place orders for customers ensuring best price and order accuracy on luxury fashion.

INTERIM SALES MANAGER, ASSISTANT MANAGER, DIGITAL STYLIST

NORDSTROM TRUNK CLUB | VIRTUAL, DALLAS, TX | AUG 2017 - JUNE 2020

Coached and developed team members on customer service and styling. Cultivated strong customer relationships, advising and styling with brand expertise and facilitating effective communications via chat and phone to deliver quota surpassing sales month over month.

- Analyzed KPI data identifying opportunities and coaching sales teams to increase performance supporting high retention and bookings of 800+ customers.
- Built book of business via chat and email ensuring excellent customer service to keep customers returning
- Styled customers according to preferences resulting in top performing metrics and setting a company wide monthly sales record of \$91,000.

KELSEY SIKES

STYLIST

AWARDS

MVP AWARD

Award for exemplifying company values in leadership and sales at Nordstrom Trunk Club.

TOP 10 SELLER

Top 10 company wide sales 6 months in a row at Nordstrom Trunk Club.

COSTUME SHOP AWARD

Award for excellence in garment construction and time management at Theater Memphis.

TESTIMONIALS

Cindy King, Sales Manager, Nordstrom Trunk Club

"A true BOSS! An inspiration and the reason our team was successful...Someone that goes above and beyond for each person because (she) truly cares about them and their success."

Laney Wilson, Digital Stylist, Nordstrom Trunk Club

"A Rockstar and leader. Someone everyone could depend on and go to. Consistently going above and beyond...and raising the bar"

EXPERIENCE (CONTINUED)

COSTUME TECHNICIAN

INDIANA REPERTORY THEATER | INDIANAPOLIS, IN | AUG 2016 - MAY 2017

Held primary administrative responsibility maintaining manager's schedule, managing in/outgoing packages and costumes, and maintaining expense tracking reports. Assisted in preparing and proofing plans, facilitating material availability, and organizing costumes inventory.

- Created and administered daily and weekly schedules managing administrative and sewing projects scheduling to deliver timely results and final projects.
- Developed and implemented expenses tracking and analysis processes using excel for show, month, and department reporting and budget management.

COSTUME TECHNICIAN

JEAN ANN RYAN PRODUCTIONS | FORT LAUDERDALE, FL | NOV 2015 - JUN 2016

Supported costume design and production aboard cruise ships, stitching and repairing performance costumes with little/no supervision and tight deadlines.

 Coordinated limited supplies and resources completing costume projects on cruise ships within time constraints and meeting designer preferences.

SALES ASSOCIATE

PARTY CITY | BLOOMINGTON, IN | SEPT 2014 - APRIL 2016

Contributed to sales and operations teams delivering exceptional customer service, training new hire sales members, processing shipments and inventory, and setting planograms.

COSTUME TECHNICIAN

THEATER MEMPHIS | MEMPHIS, TN | MAY 2014 - JAN 2016

Assisted with costume production, alterations, and repairs within tight deadlines, utilizing effective time management skills and inventory management.